<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" ?>
<!-- 
/*
 * Copyright 2001-2004 The Apache Software Foundation.
 * 
 * Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
 * you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
 * You may obtain a copy of the License at
 * 
 *      http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
 * 
 * Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
 * distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
 * WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
 * See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
 * limitations under the License.
 */
 -->

<document>

  <properties>
    <title>Housekeeper</title>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <section name="About Housekeeper">
        <p> This project's goal is to provide an application for managing 
            household issues. Currently, it is able to keep a list of food 
            inlcuding their expiry dates so you always have an overview of what 
            is going to seed soon.</p>
        <p>Please see the <a 
          href="http://developer.berlios.de/feature/?group_id=3180">Requested 
          features tracker</a> for planned features. If you have an idea for an 
          additional feature please don't hesitate to create a new entry to the 
          tracker!</p>
    </section>
    <section name="Prerequisites">
            <p>Housekeeper is compatible with every computer for which a 
                <b>Java Runtime Environment (JRE)</b> is available. This 
                includes computers running on <b>Windows 95/98/ME/2000/XP, 
                Macintosh OS X, Linux or Solaris.</b> Housekeeper runs with any 
                JRE of version 1.4 or greater.</p>
            <p>You can download a JRE for free <a 
                href="http://www.java.com">here</a>. 
                Please follow the installation instructions for the "J2SE 
                Runtime Environment (JRE)" </p>
            <p> If your operating system is Macintosh OS X or Linux you 
                probably already have a JRE installed. Make sure your 
                JRE's version is at least 1.4</p>
    </section>
    <section name="Download and installation">
		<ol>
            <li>Download Housekeeper <a 
                href="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=91396&amp;package_id=96438"> 
                here!</a> Pick the <code>.zip</code> file for Windows or the 
                <code>.tar.gz</code> file for any other platform.</li>
            <li>Decompress the ZIP or GZ archive to the location you want 
                Housekeeper to be installed. <p>If you are upgrading from an 
                older version of Housekeeper please make sure to remove that 
                version completely by deleting the folder before copying the 
                new version to the same location. Your household data will not 
                be deleted by this action because it is saved in the user's 
                home directory, not in the application's directory.</p></li>
            <li>Start Housekeeper by double-clicking on 
              <code>housekeeper-0.2.2.jar</code>.</li>
            <li>If that doesn't work start Housekeeper by double-clicking on 
                <code>housekeeper.bat</code> when running on Windows or use 
                <code>housekeeper.sh</code> on any other platform.</li>
		</ol>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
