<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" ?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Download and installation</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Prerequisites">
      <ol>
        <li> Housekeeper is compatible with these <b>operating systems</b>:
          <ul> 
            <li>Windows 95/98/ME/2000/XP</li>
            <li>Macintosh OS X</li> 
            <li>Linux</li>
            <li>Solaris</li>
            <li>Any other OS where a Java Runtime Environment 1.4.2 is available.</li>
          </ul>
        </li>
        <li>Housekeeper requires a <b>Java Runtime Environment (JRE) 1.4.2 or higher</b>.
          <ul> 
            <li><b>Windows</b> users can <a href="http://www.java.com">get a free 
               JRE at java.com</a>. Click on "Java Software Download" on the right for 
        installation instructions.</li>
            <li><b>Linux</b> users probably can install 
          Java with the software package manager tool of their distribution (for 
          example YaST or APT). Alternatively, you can <a href="http://www.java.com">get a free 
               JRE at java.com</a>.</li>
            <li><b>Mac OS X</b> already comes with Java installed. Just make sure to always have the latest system updates installed.</li>
          </ul> 
       </li>
      </ol>
		</section>
    
    <section 
        name="Automatic download and installation with Webstart">
       <p>The 
        preferred way to install Housekeeper is using <a 
        href="http://java.sun.com/j2se/1.5.0/docs/guide/javaws/developersguide/faq.html">Webstart</a>. 
        Benefits are:
         <ul>
          <li>Automatic download and installation.</li>
          <li>Creation of desktop icon and program menu entry. </li>
          <li>Automatic update of Housekeeper. If you start Housekeeper 
        and you are connected to the Internet, Webstart checks if there is an 
        update to Housekeeper. If so, the new version is automatically 
        downloaded and installed. (You can disable this behaviour)</li> 
        <li>Donwloads only those parts which changed when updating.</li>
          <li>No separate download. Webstart is included in the JRE.</li>
          </ul>
          </p>
        <p> <a 
        href="http://ftp.berlios.de/pub/housekeeper/webstart/housekeeper.jnlp"> 
        Download and install Housekeeper with Webstart now!</a> </p>
      </section> 
      
      <section name="Manual download and installation"> <p>If you don't want 
        or can't use Webstart, you can download Housekeeper as an archive and 
        install it yourself: <ol> <li>Download Housekeeper <a 
        href="http://developer.berlios.de/project/showfiles.php?group_id=3180"> 
        here!</a> Pick the <code>.zip</code> file for Windows or the 
        <code>.tar.gz</code> file for any other platform.</li> <li>Decompress 
        the ZIP or GZ archive to the location you want Housekeeper to be 
        installed. <p>If you are upgrading from an older version of Housekeeper 
        please make sure to remove that version completely by deleting the 
        folder before copying the new version to the same location. Your 
        household data will not be deleted by this action because it is saved 
        in the user's home directory, not in the application's 
        directory.</p></li> <li>Start Housekeeper by double-clicking on 
        <code>housekeeper-VERSION.jar</code>, where "VERSION" is the version 
        number of Housekeeper.</li> <li>If that doesn't work start Housekeeper 
        by double-clicking on <code>housekeeper.bat</code> when running on 
        Windows or use <code>housekeeper.sh</code> on any other platform.</li> 
        </ol> </p>
      </section> 
   </body> 
</document>